This freaks me out. Oh, I got chills
just thinking about it. And he goes,
"Five, four, three, two, one." And he
wakes up and his arm falls and he looks
around and he says, "What happened?" And
then he goes
and then vomits all over himself. I
called my boss at headquarters. I said,
"This is the craziest thing I've ever
seen." And my boss says, "I'm freaking
out over the stolen license plate." I
have to tell you the the one operation
that I did with a with an agency
psychologist was the most fun I have
ever had in a single operation.
We had a walk-in.
We had a walk a walk-in is somebody who
literally walks in to an to an American
embassy off the street and says, "I have
intelligence I want to pass to the CIA."
95% of them are lunatics.
the the other 5% are intelligence
peddlers who just want you to give them
a couple hundred dollars and then they
go to the British embassy and the
Russian embassy and the French embassy
and the Israeli embassy and they just do
the same thing and then that's a month's
salary, right? Um some are uh
probes from terrorist groups or enemy
countries. They're just looking to see
where the cameras are, how thick the
doors are, who's armed or not armed, how
far into the embassy they can get before
they're stopped.
But most of them are just lunatics.
And then there's 1% that's the real
deal. If you look historically
by reading Cold War era memoirs, the
best recruits the CIA has ever had were
walk-ins. Because you don't know who
this Russian KGB colonel is. You're
never going to encounter him. But then
one day, he just walks into an embassy
somewhere and says, "I'm a KGB colonel
and I want to give you everything I have
and I want a million dollars." And you
say, "I'll get the giant sack of money."
you start writing. You know, I'm being
facitious, of course, but not too much.
So, we had a walk-in who said that he
had seen an assassination.
He he said that he's driving down this
highway and he has to take a leak. And
so, he pulls off an exit and there's
this old abandoned church there and he
parks his car behind this big banyan
tree and he takes he's taking a leak.
And while he's taking a leak,
a van pulls up.
A bunch of guys get out of the back of
the van.
The source sees two motorcycles in the
back of the van. And here's one of the
guys say, "Does he still live?" And the
other one says, "He should be dead by
now."
So
he says, "I think this was this
terrorist group that you guys are
after." And we said, "Will you sit with
a sketch artist?" He said, "Yes."
And he did the sketches and they were
really, really close to photographs we
had of people that we suspected were in
this terrorist group.
So, we turned him over to the FBI and
the FBI interviewed him. They said,
"He's full of [__] He's nuts. We're
done.
Well, we just took him back and we said,
"How about if we fly to London,
we have a nice dinner, everybody's
relaxed, we're all friends, and we talk
about this in more detail." He said,
"Great." So, we fly him to London. He
was so poor, the poor guy. I remember
this. He flew to London. was freezing
and he didn't own a coat. So, I went out
and bought him a coat uh just so he
wouldn't, you know, be frozen solid by
the end of the the 3 or 4 days. So, I
flew out to London with two
psychologists, but one of the
psychologists was a licensed hypnotist
and um
and I flew out there with another case
officer. So, we both spoke the language
and so we're going to act as translators
for the hypnotist.
It's hard work being a translator. And
let me tell you, and you have to be like
speaking like this. We're going to count
backwards. 10 9 8. It's very hard.
So
the night before
we go out to some bookstore, we go to a
nice restaurant without the guy. The guy
hasn't arrived yet. So just the agency
people. We went out. This is going to be
our plan. We're going to, you know, have
all the lights off. We're going to be in
the darkened hotel room, speak very
softly. We're going to put them under.
And I said, "Come on." I said, I said,
"Hypnosis isn't really a thing, right?"
It always just seemed like [__] to
me. And he said, "No, no, no." He said,
"We're going to we're going to really
put him under." And he said, 'You know,
the funny thing is that smart people go
under much more quickly than stupid
people do, which I still don't fully
understand, but he said, "We're going to
we're going to ask him all these
questions." I said, "Well, how long does
this last?" He said, "If if we get him
under quickly,
we could do this for two and a half or
three hours." I'm like, okay, this is
going to be tough being the translator.
So, the guy arrives and you know,
welcome. This is Dr. So and so, this is
the other Dr. So and so, and you know,
my colleague, and so, you know, get
comfortable. You need a drink or you've
used the bathroom. We're going to we're
going to hypnotize you to help you
remember some of the things that you saw
that day.
So,
this is one of the wackiest things that
ever I ever witnessed at the agency.
So,
I was the first translator and I told
him, "We're going to count backwards
from 10 and just relax and think about
the numbers." Right? So, we start and he
said, "I want you to raise your hand
like this." And it wasn't propped. It
was up in the air like this. And he
said, "Don't put your hand down until I
tell you to."
He held his arm there for 3 hours.
It was inhuman.
A conscious person couldn't do it.
So the guy is out before we get to zero,
counting back from 10. So,
I start asking him questions. Okay, you
pull off the exit. You drive to the
church. The church is right off to the
side of the road. You go behind the
banyan tree.
Then what are you doing? He said, "I'm
peeing."
And then what happens? A van pulls up.
What does the van look like? It's
painted red and it has some rust spots
over the the rear wheels.
Then what do you see?
The back door is open. I see two
motorcycles and two men inside. I said,
"Can you see a license plate?" This
freaks me out. Oh, I got chills just
thinking about it. I said, "Can you see
a license plate?" He says, "Yes." And
his he's like this with his eyes closed.
I said, "What does the license plate
say?" and he goes
and then he reads off the plate. So I
write it down. I hand it to my
colleague. He goes into the other room
and he calls headquarters. He says, "We
need to run a plate ASAP."
So headquarters sends an immediate cable
out to the field. Call liaison. Run this
plate right now. And the plate comes
back stolen.
I couldn't [__] believe it. I
couldn't believe it. And he's like this
the whole time. So I said, "Are the men
talking?" "Yes." "What are they saying?
Does he still live? He should be dead by
now." And then what happens? And he
says, "They see me."
I said, "They see you. Do they approach
you?" He said, "Yes." And one punches me
in the face.
And then what? He said, "I'm bleeding."
And I told them, "I didn't hear
anything." And he went on like this. It
was this long elaborate three-hour long
story.
So I took notes like ridiculous, you
know, filled a notebook full of notes.
I called my boss at headquarters. I
said, "This is the craziest thing I've
ever seen." And my boss says, "I'm
freaking out over the stolen license
plate." He goes, "This may be the real
deal."
I I write all the notes. I go back to
the station in London. I I write all the
notes and I send it back out into the
field and they're like, "Oh my god, the
details incredible." Okay, we're going
to try to get with him when he returns
to country. So, a couple of weeks pass
and then he triggers a meeting
and so my colleague who I'd been with in
London flies out to meet with him and
the guy says, "They know who I am. They
kidnapped me and they took me to a house
and they beat me.
And we're like, "Okay, where where was
the house? When did this happen? How
many of them were there? What did they
look like? Were this were they the same
guys you saw at the church?" He answered
all these questions.
And I said to my colleague, I said,
"This doesn't make sense because the
only way they would know who he was is
if they were, you know, with us.
We knew where he lived, but there's no
way that they would know." It just
didn't make any sense. So, I go to the
FBI
and it there's this one agent. She's
actually big mucky muck now in the FBI.
And she goes, "You CIA people, you all
have your heads up your asses," she
said. And I said, "No, you FBI people."
I said, "You think everybody's lying to
you." I said, "We're going to get medals
when we crack this case." And she goes,
"Ah, you people." So, she wasn't helpful
to me.
Then he calls a second time and he says
um that they kidnapped him again, but he
had a tape recorder on him and the tape
recorder was in his pocket and he
recorded the whole encounter. We're
like, "Okay,
that's way too good to be true, but
let's listen to the tape." So,
we play the tape and he's like, it's his
voice and he says, "Hey, I know you.
Don't hurt me." And then also his voice,
"I am the Minister of Public Order and I
demand that you tell me about the CIA
people that you're meeting with." And I
was like, "Motherfucker,
you made the whole [__] thing up,
didn't you?
So, we decided to fly him back out to
London. Oh, let me finish the first part
first. So, he's got his arm like this.
And the hypnotist says, "I'm going to
count backwards to five and then you're
going to wake up." And he goes 5 4 3 2
1. And he wakes up and his arm falls and
he looks around and he says, "What
happened?" And then he goes
and then vomits all over himself. So he
runs into the bathroom in the hotel room
to clean himself up. And the hypnotist
who was like 110 years old, he goes,
"You know, I've read about this in the
literature, but I've never seen it
happen." I said, "I can't believe he
held his arm up like that for 3 hours.
It was nuts." So anyway, we fly him back
out to London.
We said, "No more [__] You made
this up." No, no. It was the Minister of
Public Order. He's with the terrorists.
We're like, "No, we we ran a spectros a
spectroscope on this. It's it's you with
your hand over your mouth to try to make
a different voice." And he's like, "Oh,
well, my wife has cancer and I I was
hoping that if you believed me that you
would pay for her cancer treatment and I
wanted her to go to the Mayo Clinic."
And we're like, "Doesn't work that way."
And then the FBI just says, "I told you,
you [__] idiots. I told you three
months ago it was a lie." So I was like,
"Yeah, okay. Well, you win this one."
>> But the hypnosis part was actually that
was real.
>> That that he saw something at the church
that day. It probably wasn't the
terrorists,
but it was something unoured. It was
probably a bunch of guys that stole two
motorcycles.
>> What's up, guys? Thank you so much for
taking the time to watch the interview.
If you got anything out of this video at
all, please like the video, leave me a
comment, tell me what you thought of the
video. Uh, tell me who you'd like to see
on the show. I really appreciate the
support. It goes a long way on these
platforms, as you guys know. Most
importantly, I have some excellent
interviews coming up in the future that
I'm really, really excited about. So,
please subscribe to the channel so you
don't miss any of them. But that's it.
Thank you for your support.